Miguel Martin Soriano Talaverano

miguel mst@hotmail.com / +51 992769850

Summary

I am a Senior .Net Developer with more than 15 years of experience in many Microsoft tools and platforms. I am dynamic, responsible, with organization capacity, ability for working in group and under pressure, fast learning capacity, advanced English level.

Formal Education

- Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos, Lima, Perú.
 - Computer Systems Engineer (2006)
- Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos, Lima, Perú.
 - o Computer Science Bachelor (1999 2005)

Programming Skills

- Programming Languages / Technologies: Azure (+1 year), .Net Core (+4 years), REST Services (+6 years),
 .Net (+15 years), C# (+12 years), LINQ (+2 year), Auto Mapper (+2 years) Xamarin (1 year), Asp (1 year), Visual Basic (4 years), jQuery (5 years), JavaScript (2 years), WinForms (3 years), WCF Service (2 years), Service Stack (4 years),
- Databases: MS SQL Server (+10 years), MySQL (1 year)
- Operating systems: Windows 10, Windows XP.
- IDEs: Microsoft Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Microsoft Visual Basic 6
- CMS: WordPress, Orchard, Drupal
- Data Modeling: UML Rational Rose, Erwin
- Other technologies: XML (+1 year), Angular (+2 year), SVN, Git, DevExpress (6 months), KendoUI (6 months),
 HL7 (1 year).
- Agile methodologies: SCRUM (+10 years).
- English: Good Spoken, Good Written and Read.

Certifications

- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals (2023)
- Certified Scrum Master (2014)
- Microsoft® Certified Technology Specialist: .Net Framework 2.0, Web Applications (2008)

Founder of TuEscenaOnline (https://www.tuescenaonline.com/ - 2022)

I merged my two passions (systems engineering and acting) in this personal project. It is a streaming platform in
which producers, theater groups or individual artist can expose their work (recorded videos) and users can
subscribe to have unlimited access to the content (videos, photos and interviews).

<u>Technologies used</u>: Net core 3.1, C#, Entity Framework Core, LINQ, Azure Integration (App Service, Blob Storage, Service Bus/Queues, Key Vault, Application Insight, Azure Functions, SQL Database), Git, Slack integration, PayPal integration, SendGrid integration, DynTube integration, REST APIs, Swagger, JWT, IdentityServer4, AutoMapper, MVC, Razor, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery.

Experience

WHIZ LATAM - Lima - Perú (2021 - 2023)

Client: New Mile - USA

o Role: Sr. .Net Developer

o **Description:** FullStack developer in charge of solving issues at the frontend and backend layer.

Responsibilities: Analysis, Design, Development and Testing

Technologies & Tools: C#, Net Framework 4.7, CSS, SCSS, Angular, CQRS, REST Services, Git,
 Jira, Agile.

o **Duration:** 03/2023 to 04/2023

Client: EY (Ernst & Young) / UMB - USA

o Role: Sr. .Net Developer

 Description: Responsible for creating API Integrations using Microservices, based on swagger documentation. Execution of requirements defined by the client, coding and resolutions of issues.

o Responsibilities: Analysis, Design, Development and Testing

Technologies & Tools: C#, .Net Core, Rest Services, Visual Studio, NUnit, XUnit, Moq,
 AutoMapper, Swagger, SOAP UI, Insomnia, Git, TFS, Fiserv, Tsys, Scrum

Duration: 05/2021 to 02/2023

Globant – Lima – Perú (2019 to 2021)

Client: Kantar - USA / INDIA

o Role: Sr. Software Developer

 Description: Responsible for the execution and implementation of applications on Microsoft .NET platform. Execution of requirements defined by the client, coding and resolutions of issues.

Responsibilities: Analysis, Design, Development and Testing

 Main Technologies: Azure (AppServices, BlobStorage, AzureFunctions, AppInsight, KeyVault, ServiceBus, AppInsights), C#.Net Core, Rest Services, SQL, LINQ, Scrum and Git.

Duration: 11/2020 to 05/2021

Client: Chatham Financial - USA

o Role: Sr. Software Developer

 Description: Responsible for the execution and implementation of applications on Microsoft .NET platform. Execution of requirements defined by the client, coding and resolutions of issues.

Responsibilities: Analysis, Design, Development and Testing

o Main Technologies: C#.Net Core, Rest Services, SQL, LINQ, Jira, Scrum, SVN and Git.

Duration: 05/2019 to 10/2020

Belatrix Software Factory – Lima – Perú (2013 to 2019)

Client: Brainkshark - USA

- o Role: Sr. Software Developer
- Description: Responsible for the execution and implementation of applications on Microsoft .NET platform like MVC applications, Rest Microservices. Execution of requirements defined by the client, coding and resolutions of issues.
- o Responsibilities: Analysis, Design, Development and Testing
- Main Technologies: ASP, VB 6.0, C#.Net, Net. Core, Rest Services, SQL, LINQ, MVC, SVN and Git.
- Duration: 09/2018 to 04/2019

Client: Chatham Financial - USA

- o Role: Sr. Software Developer
- Description: Responsible for the execution and implementation of applications on Microsoft .NET platform. Execution of requirements defined by the client, coding and resolutions of issues.
- Responsibilities: Analysis, Design, Development and Testing
- Main Technologies: C#.Net, WCF/Rest Services, Service Stack, SQL, LINQ, WebApps, MVC,
 jQuery, Angular JS, Jira, Scrum, SVN and Git.
- o **Duration:** 06/2013 to 08/2018

Chicago Code Monkeys – Lima – Perú (2009 to 2013)

Project: Web Development for State Serv Medical - USA

- o Role: Net. Developer
- Description: web-based project to manage Medical Information related to older people to have the right equipment handy at home or another place they are. The application interchanges information with other medical entities in HL7 format to have their patient's information updated. Also, the application allows to order medical devices for patients at specific places. In addition, the system allows to have partners to offer the same service.
- o Responsibilities: maintenance and implementation of new features.
- Main Technologies: NET Framework 4.0, ASP.NET, ASP, Ajax, jQuery, C#, SqlServer 2008, MVC
 3.0 Razor, Kendo UI.
- Duration: Around 1 year.

Project: Web Development for Business Opportunity - USA

- o Role: Net. Developer
- Description: web-based project to help small companies / business to offer their knowledge / background in order to help people a good way to invest their money. The application has two parts: Public site, in which interested people can see all announcements and details about them; and an Intranet application, in which offering companies can enter their announcements and manages their potential clients.
- Responsibilities: maintenance and implementation of new features.

- o Main Technologies: NET Framework 4.0, ASP.NET, jQuery, C#, Sql Server 2008, MVC 3.0 Razor
- Duration: Around 1 year.

Project: Web Development for Certified Knowledge - USA

- o Role: Net. Developer
- Description: web-based project to offer SEO (Search Engine Optimization) tools.
- Responsibilities: Implementation of new set of tools.
- o Main Technologies: NET Framework 2, ASP.NET, jQuery, JavaScript, C#, MVC 1.0 Razor
- Duration: Around 1 year.

Project: Web Development for Cardio Choices - USA

- o Role: Net. Developer
- Description: Content management system (Orchard), modified based on client's need, which offer the ability to find a cardiologist near to your place, as well as important information related to the heart.
- o Responsibilities: maintenance and implementation of new features.
- Main Technologies: NET Framework 3.5, ASP.NET, jQuery, C#, MVC 1.0 Razor
- Duration: Around 6 months.

Project: Web Development for Eco Global Logistic - USA

- o Role: Net. Developer
- Description: web-based project to manage delivery of orders around the world.
- Responsibilities: maintenance and implementation of new features.
- o Main Technologies: NET Framework 2.0, ASP.NET, jQuery, Ajax, C#
- o **Duration:** Around 8 months.

Nexogy SAC – Lima – Perú (2007 to 2009)

Project: Web Development for internal modules / applications - USA

- o **Role:** Analyst / Net Developer
- Description: Telecommunication Company, in which I participate in analysis and codification of different systems or modules that are used by this company to help making their business efficient. Software application projects, which have the following modules: Helpdesk, Lead System, Credit Cards, Security, Invoicing.
- o **Responsibilities:** maintenance and implementation of new features.
- o Main Technologies: NET Framework 1.0 / 2.0, ASP.NET, VB, Sql Server 2000
- o **Duration:** 2007 to 2009.

LDTelecom SAC – Lima – Perú (2003 to 2007)

Project: Web Development for internal modules / applications – USA

- o **Role:** Support / Developer
- Description: Telecommunication Company.
- Responsibilities: Support / Helpdesk / Developer

- Main Technologies: Support. Computer Configuration, Operating Systems XP, Windows 2000 and 2003. Exchange Server 2000 Maintenance and Configuration. Programming using Visual FoxPro 8.0, Visual Studio .NET 2003 and Microsoft SQL 2000
- Duration: 2003 to 2007.

Additional Education

- AZ-9000 MS Azure Fundamentals 16 hours New Horizons 2023 (Certified)
 - o https://www.credly.com/badges/900b0cb5-8546-4ab9-bcee-dc03f5839270/public_url
- Certification course CSM Certified Scrum Master 16 hours Hubert Smits 2014 (Certified)
- Microsoft® Certified Technology Specialist: .Net Framework 2.0, Web Applications New Horizons 2008
 (Certified)
- Maintaining a Microsoft SQL Server 2008 Database 24 hours New Horizons 2009
- Implementing a Microsoft SQL Server 2008 Database 24 hours New Horizons 2009
- Visual Studio 2008: Windows Communication Foundation 18 hours New Horizons 2009
- Visual Studio 2008: Windows Presentation Foundation 18 hours New Horizons 2009
- Visual Studio 2008: ASP.NET 3.5 18 hours New Horizons 2009
- Visual Studio 2008: ADO.NET 3.5 18 hours New Horizons 2009
- Advanced Foundation of Microsoft .NET 2.0 Development 20 hours New Horizons 2009
- Core Foundation of Microsoft .NET 2.0 Development 20 hours New Horizons 2009
- Maintaining a Microsoft SQL Server 2005 Database 24 hours New Horizons 2008
- Implementing a Microsoft SQL Server 2005 Database 24 hours New Horizons 2008
- Applications Development with .Net Framework 2.0 20 hours New Horizons 2008
- Core Data Access Development with Visual Studio 2005 20 hours New Horizons 2008
- Advanced Data Access Development with Visual Studio 2005 18 hours New Horizons 2008
- Core Web Applications Development with Visual Studio 2005 18 hours New Horizons 2008
- Advanced Web Applications Development with Visual Studio 2005 18 hours New Horizons 2008
- Core Windows Applications Development with Visual Studio 2005 18 hours New Horizons 2008
- Advanced Windows Applications Development with Visual Studio 2005 18 hours New Horizons 2008
- Core Distributed Application Development with Visual Studio 2005 20 hours New Horizons 2008
- Advanced Distributed Application Development with Visual Studio 2005 20 hours New Horizons 2008
- Net Developer Specialist 48 hours U. Nacional de Ingeniería 2005
- Specialist in Security and Network Administration 48 hours U. Nacional de Ingeniería 2005
- Design and Developing Applications using Visual Basic language program 40 hours U. Nacional de Ingeniería
 2005
- Computers Assembly 20 hours U. Nacional de Ingeniería 2000

Acting Career | Lima - Perú (+7 years):

- Acting Training Workshop:
 - o 2018 Leonardo Torres Vilar (1 year)
 - o 2017 Mikhail Page (1 year)
 - 2016 Roberto Angeles (8 months)
- Plays:
- Virtual (Live Streaming):
 - (2022) Despedida en 3 partes
 - (2021) Sincera Confesión
 - (2021) Estoy Muerto
 - (2020) Pequeños Héroes
- o Theather:
 - (2022) Mañana me caso
 - (2020) Contra Viento y Marea
 - (2019) Escuela para Hombres
 - (2019) No hay terapia que resulte
 - (2019) Nos Volveremos a Encontrar
 - (2018) El Verano pasado en Chulimsk
 - (2017) Nuestro Pueblo
 - (2017) Adiós al Camino Amarillo
- Movies:
 - o (2019) Django en el Nombre del Hijo (Character: Huachano)
- Tv Commercials:
 - o (2020) Interbank Es tiempo de detener la violencia

Hobbies

- Learning technologies
- Watching movies
- Playing basketball